Now friends, before moving ahead in the video,
I would like to give you a small disclaimer
that brother, this video is being
made for educational purposes.
Before taking any financial decision,
do your own research or if
you have a financial advisor, then
definitely take advice from him.  Now let's move on to the
next side of the video.  Now look friends,
this happens many times that if we have
an old car or even if we
purchase a new car, then its
insurance is an obvious thing,
we get it automatically for one year from the
showroom.  But brother, if your
car is more than a year old
and if you want to purchase its insurance,
then brother, this video is going to be very
useful for you because even if you get the
insurance done offline or
through your showroom, then
here you have to pay 20 to 25%
extra money because friends, those
people take away their commission.  But in today's
video I am going to tell you the direct
method.  How can you get your car
insured?
While getting the vehicle insured in Plus, we get to
see three types of segments here.
First is our third party
insurance, second is our first party
insurance and third is our comprehensive
plan.  Look friend, in case of bike we
understand that it is a small amount, we will
take our first party.  But
friends, if a car case comes there, then
brother, your amount here
increases a lot
in first party and third party cases.  So brother,
whatever decision you take,
take it after thinking carefully.  Whatever I am going to tell you, please
listen to it carefully.  So friends,
here we first talk about third
party insurance.  Because brother,
maximum people get this done because this is the
cheapest.  Let us assume that
brother, if your vehicle is in running condition
and brother, if you keep driving it and
if you have taken third party insurance
and brother, if by any chance the police
catches you, then nothing will be done to you at that time
because brother, you already have
third party insurance.  Now
people will think that if you have third party
insurance and the police is not saying anything then
why do you get first party insurance done
?  So brother, there is a catch here.
If you take third party insurance then
brother, the police will not say anything to you.
But whenever the insurance company assumes that
God forbid, if your vehicle meets with an
accident, then at that time
you will not be given any claim because
third party insurance always says
that if your vehicle has met with an accident and
in that case you want to take a claim, then
we will not give you any claim.
But yes, if you have suffered any loss due to your own vehicle or the
vehicle of the other party, then in
that case this
third party insurance
provides the claim to the other party.
This means that brothers move ahead with respect, for example,
if I am going in my car
and some car is coming from that side.  If there is a
collision between these two, then brother, the
third party insurance will
not give me the claim.  He will give the claim to this party
because this third party
covers the other party.  And brother, one thing
you have to keep in mind is that
if you have a third party
plan, it is obvious that there will be some
insurance for it as well.  And if
both of them collide.  Now whether it is
first party or third party.
You can also get the claim here.
So brother, that is why I say that whenever
your car meets with an accident, do
not argue at that time.  You all should share your numbers etc.
among yourselves and whenever it is your
turn to take a claim, you should take your claim
from the other person's insurance and the
other party will take the claim from your insurance.
But friends,
our environment is not good every time.  Sometimes things go wrong.
So brother, in this case
first party insurance comes to our rescue.  Now
friends, let us assume that if you have
taken first party insurance, then brother,
first party insurance says that
brother, I will save you from the police also.  If
your vehicle meets with an accident, I will
also provide you a claim in that case.
Because in first party case,
if your car gets hit by anything.
Look friend, whenever you make a claim, the
claim you get is from only one side.
You cannot claim the vehicle from both sides.
Whether it is in our bike
case or in our car case,
brother, no company accepts your claim from both sides.
You have to keep this thing in
mind.  If we assume that
your car is hit from one side and you
want to claim from one side, then brother,
you are given the claim under the first party.
But even within the first party, the
company does not provide claims for our consumable items.  Now
look, if we leave aside the consumable atom, then even
your engine is not covered under the first party.
You have to take care of this thing.  The
engine is basically your add-on
which you have to take.  And
look, these add-ons
form a comprehensive plan of our mix
or this is also called our zero depth.
Brother, this is
our third party at the lowest level.  Above that is our
first party and above that is
our comprehensive plan or zero
depth plan.  Whenever you buy a new car
from the showroom, your zero depth is running at that time.  If there is
any damage inside the vehicle, the company easily passes your claim by removing any consumable item X or Z.
But at the same time, if your
car gradually becomes old.
If you take first party here then
brother, engine etc. are not covered at that time.
Now look friends, whenever we
apply for insurance, I will
explain more things to you.  But for now let
us see which of our
companies is the best for getting insurance
online as of today.  So look, here
we will use Acco application.  Look friend, there
is no sponsor etc.  I am getting it done in Acco
basically to get my own personal vehicle
insured.   That's why
I am recommending it to you too.
You can insure your vehicle yourself through Acco.
So let me show you how to
insure through it in this video.
So friends, here you
can see that you have reached the Maco website.
I will give you its direct link
inside the description box below.
Here your minimum insurance
starts from ₹294
and brother, within just 2 minutes you
can renew the insurance of your vehicle or car or you
can also buy a new one.  Even if you are purchasing a new car,
you can buy its insurance here.
You simply have to
click on check price.  Otherwise brother, if you
want to renew your insurance, then
here you have to enter your vehicle number and simply
click on check price.
Now look, I am recommending this one to you
because brother, my own
car insurance is done through this one.
Here you
get the facility of instant claim settlement.  If
you want to take any minor claim etc. then
brother, you can see it instantly.
But brother, if you have any major
claim then it may take some
time for verification.  And here
you can see that
their claim settlement ratio in the financial year 2023-24 was
99.10%.  Otherwise, if you scroll down a little,
you will
get some more information about it.  Like here
you get 24*7 support.
Facility of easy insurance renewal
is available.  There are many more things.  Let
me show you here.  If you
want to purchase insurance for a new car, then simply
come here and
click on View Price.  After that, here
you have to click on select make and model of your vehicle
and here you have to select whatever car you have.  For example, let
me take
Tata Nexon here.  After that,
under fuel type, I have to tell whether it is petrol or
diesel.  So brother, let me fill petrol here.
After that, what is its variant
?  So for example, I am
filling up everything and you will have to
tell me when is the delivery date of our car.
So brother, see, you can select any one from these.
After that here
we are asking, brother, do you have a commercial
vehicle?  So brother, we said no here.
After that finally we will click on continue.
Now here you can see that whatever
is your mobile number and whatever is your pin
code, you have to give it and click on Simply View Plan.
So brother, look, this was a case.
If you purchase a new car.  But
friends, if you want to get your vehicle renewed, then
simply you have to
come back here and now
click on Enter Your Car Number which you can see here and
finally you have to click on Check Price.
So friends, here you can see that
we have entered our vehicle number here.
Our registration date is coming here.  The
variant is coming and which model
number is it.  After that, if you
want, brother, you can also edit it.  Now he is
asking us, brother, have you got
any CNG kit etc. installed from outside?  So brother,
no, we have not got it installed.  After that we will have to
enter our phone number here and
after entering our pin code we simply have to
click on view plans.  Now friends,
here you can see that whatever premium etc. of our car is there,
it is being shown to us first.
Here you will
see an IDV value.  Here
my IDV value is being told in the middle as
1.98 lakh and I can
enter a maximum amount of ₹2,86,000 in the IDV
value.  If you do
not know the IDV value then brother, let me tell you once.  Let us
assume that I have
taken my IDV value as ₹1,98,000 and if my car gets
stolen or catches fire
, gets accidentally damaged
and becomes a total loss, then brother,
whatever IDV value I have
selected, I will
get the same amount of money here.  That's why friends, I
say that you should always keep your IDV value
high.  Now friends, here
you can see that we are being given two plans here.
One is our comprehensive
plan and the other is our zero depreciation plan.  That
means friends, you
can see our plan here, it is for ₹126.
But our comprehensive plan is of
₹5434.  Right now we are
not able to find any third party in this.  Otherwise, the
third party one would have been a little cheaper.
Here, let me
tell you what
differences we see in both these plans.  Here
you can see that if I
talk about comprehensive plan, then brother,
whatever accidental expenses you incur, i.e. repair etc.,
the company will bear that.
After that, if your car catches fire,
she will also keep you company.  If your vehicle gets
stolen, you will get a claim for that also.
If there is
any damage to your vehicle due to climate, then
you will be given a claim for that too. Rats bites damage
means that friends, if there is any
damage to your vehicle due to rat bites, then
you will be given a claim for that too and
if there is injury or death of a third party, then the
company will settle that claim as well and
if the property of a third party gets damaged, the
company will also settle that and friends, let
me tell you once what it does not cover,
as you can see here,
non-accidental damage means such
parts which keep on wearing and tearing
like tyres, tubes and engine, so brother, all these
parts are
not covered under your comprehensive plan,
if we talk about commercial use of car, that means
friends, if you start using your vehicle for
delivery or transport etc., then
brother, even at that time the company will
not give a claim and if there is pre-existing
damage, that is,
if you have any damage before getting the insurance, then the
company will not cover that also and
brother, no company covers illegal driving.  It is not there at all.
Rest of the friends, if I tell you about zero depth, then
here you can see that it
covers 100% of the car parts etc.  If he is a replacement then
brother, he is also replaced.  That's the only
thing you do
n't get here.  As I told you that
our bear end gear inside the engine is
not covered inside our comprehensive.  But
that gets covered under zero depreciation.  That's why
our premium is so expensive.  Now
friends, here you can see that our
car runs very little.  So the
IDV value I have kept is
₹1.1 lakh and here I have
selected my compressive plan.  Look
friend, I am telling you that if your
car is being driven a lot then in that case
you have to increase the IDV value a
little.  One more thing to keep in
mind is that if you
increase or decrease the IDV value, then your
insurance will increase or decrease accordingly.  And
I have already explained to you the variants of the plan etc.
Now let me finally proceed with this.
Now here you can see that it is
trying to give us this extra add on.
Here you can see things like
engine protection, extra car
protection, that is, you will get
to see many things here.  If you
want to take it, you can take it brother.  Otherwise you simply have to
skip it.  But
friends, you can skip only on one condition.
If you already have one here, you
can see that if you do not edit, you agree that
you have active personal accidental or
health cover of Rs 15 lakh and above.  That means
friends, if you already have any personal
accidental or health insurance
which is worth Rs 15 lakh or more, then
brother, you can skip this.
Otherwise you can see here brother, it is
mandatory that you will have to take it here.
But friends, we already have
our personal insurance.  So
brother, let us skip this.  Now friends,
here you can see that we will have to enter some of our
reward personal details.  Like
we have to enter the full name here.
After that you have to enter your email ID.
You have to enter the mobile number here.
And after this, you have to enter the name of the company whose insurance you had purchased last time.
And here you have to tell your new policy
start date i.e. when do you want to start your policy.
If you have GST number etc. then
you can enter that also here.  So
let me enter everything and
click on continue.  Now friends, here you
can see that OTP will be sent to our phone number.
I have to enter that OTP here
and finally I have to click on Verify.
Now here we are getting the
option of review details.  That means
friends, whatever things we have filled, we have to
review them once.  As you
can see, everything is fine with us brother.  Which is
showing our premium breakup.
You have to pay 18% GST here and
your net premium comes to ₹5434.
So here you can see that
our total will be ₹6412.
So then let's click on Pay Now here.
Now friends, to complete the payment,
you can use whichever method you want here like PhonePe, Google Pay.
We select one of these.
Here you can see that we have
selected our debit or credit card.  You simply have to enter the card number,
expiry date, CVV, then you have to
accept their terms and conditions and
finally you have to click on Pay Now.
Now OTP will come on the mobile number linked with the credit card.
I have to enter that OTP here
and finally I have to
click on the submit button.  Here you
can finally see that our insurance
purchase has been done.  Our payment is complete.
But friends, now we will have to get our
KYC done.  And brother, see,
KYC becomes mandatory for us.  IRDAI on s.
Brother, after January 1, 2023, you will have to get your
KYC done if you are
purchasing insurance online, so let
us click on the Start KYC button here.
Here you can see that to get
KYC done you
need your PAN card.  You need an address proof
or if you want, you
can also get your KYC done through DigiLocker.  So let
us simply proceed with this.
Now friends, your phone
number will appear here first.  After that, here you have to
give your full name as your government
ID.  After that you have to accept their terms and conditions
and finally
click on continue.
You will have to provide your basic details on the next page.  Like
here you have to first give your PAN card
number.  After that,
enter your date of birth and then
finally you have to click on proceed.
Here you can see on the next page that
brother, our KYC has been done.
Here we
completed our KYC using our Digilocker.  Our
screen had become blurred.  Here you
can see that I finally click on Continue.
Now friends, our
KYC etc. has been done here and after that
our policy has also been issued
and you have to wait for 3 to 4 minutes here.
Whatever your policy is, you can
see it in PDF format.  If
I show you on this website, then here
you can see that the name of our vehicle is
coming here and whatever policy etc. of our vehicle is there,
I can also see it from here.
Here you can see that
you get to see the details of the entire policy.
And brother, if there is a policeman or
anyone else and you go to make a claim etc., then
you simply have to show this soft copy to
him.  Through this your work will be done
here.  But brother, please save it.
This just shouldn't happen.
Here you can see that you
get the option to download etc.